Guide to the Vassar College History Department Records, 1915-1985
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College History Department Records
1915-1985
Vassar College History Department
12 cubic feet (12 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Course material, annual reports and other material relating to the devlopment of the department.
Administrative History
There was a Department of History and Political Economy at the opening of Vassar College in 1865, but there were no history faculty. History classes were often taught by the college president. It wasn't until 1887 that the first history professor, Lucy Maynard Salmon, was hired. It was Salmon who created an independant history department at Vassar.
Scope and Content Note
Course material, annual reports and other material relating to the devlopment of the department.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Subjects:
History--Study and teaching
VCL Categories
Vassar College Academic Departments and Programs
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, June2012.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the History Department in 2007 and 2012 (A2007-019, A2012-012 and A2012-015).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The audio tapes in Box 12 will require reformatting at the researcher's expense before use.
Container List
- Annual Reports, 1924-1969 (Box 12)
- American Culture Program, 1957 (Box 12)
- Vassar Graduates with Ph.D's, 1975 (Box 12)
- Table of Majors by percentage, 1931-1975 (Box 12)
- History Schoo-College Conference, 1947 (Box 12)
- Emeriti (Box 12)
- Recordings of History Department events and unidentified reels, (reel-to-reel tapes) (Box 12)
- Miscellaneous (Box 12)
- Comprehensive Exams, 1937-1967 (Box 12)
- Exam Sheets, 1915-1927 (Box 12)
- Course Materials, 1943 (Box 12)
- Course Materials, Pre-1970-1971 (Box 1)
- Course Materials, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- Course Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Course Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Course Materials, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Course Materials, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Course Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Course Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
- Course Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
- Course Materials, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
- Course Materials, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
- Course Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
- Course Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
- Course Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
- Course Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 7)
- Course Materials, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
- Course Materials, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
- Course Materials, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
- Course Materials, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
- Course Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
- Course Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 10)
- Course Materials, 1983-1984 (Box 10)
- Course Materials, 1983-1984 (Box 11)
- Course Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
- Course Materials, 1984-1985 (Box 12)